製作: 星際迷航中國字幕組 (https://www.startrekchina.org)
翻譯: 諾北 & 中二的老馬 & rubin & σ-algebra & 小羊 & Zelpens
校對: Imprinting & narwhrl
時軸: narwhrl
特效: narwhrl
日期: 2025-08-05
《星際迷航：新世界》前情提要
Previously on Star Trek: Strange New Worlds...
佩利亞中校
Commander Pelia,
這是斯考特上尉 他需要你的幫助
this is Lieutenant Scott. He needs your help.
我認識斯考特
I know Scotty.
教授
Professor.
在人類文化中
Is it not tradition
隆重的浪漫表達 難道不是傳統嗎
to make a grand romantic gesture,
還是我又對人類的關係產生誤解了
or have I again mistaken how human relationships work?
你和克莉絲汀不是決定
I thought you and Christine
暫時分開 給彼此一點個人空間嗎
had decided to give each other some space.
確實
Indeed.
史波克
Spock.
克莉絲汀
Christine.
這是科爾比博士
This is... Dr. Korby.
我的約會對象
My date.
艦長
Captain,
我們又探測到了那個太空輻射
we're picking up that space radiation again.
無論如何
Whatever this is
它都不像是布魯塔星雲的本土產物
does not appear to be native to the Blootar Nebula.
這是在太空 上尉
This is space, Lieutenant.
沒有什麼所謂的 本土
There's no such thing as... native.
我們都是宇宙的孩子
We're all children... of the cosmos.
艦長 在過去一小時內
Cap, in the past hour,
我們又有十四名船員
we have had 14 more crew members report
因憂鬱症去醫務室報道
to medbay on account of melancholia.
我這輩子只見過一次這種場面
I have seen this only once before...
在戰場上
in the war.
那我們需要點幫助了
Then we'll need a leg up.
但是艦長 我們不在管制星域內啊
But Captain, we're outside of regulation space.
跟我談管轄權你還太嫩了 上尉
Don't lecture me on jurisdiction, Lieutenant!
太空管轄權的書 可是我編的
I wrote the book on space... jurisdiction.
而我最出名的可就是
And I am known for my...
語言措辭
diction.
好了
Now...
給我聯繫 艾戈尼亞人
...get me... the Agonyans.
艾戈尼亞人是極其危險的太空生物
The Agonyans are extremely dangerous space creatures.
你以為我不知道嗎
You don't think I know that?!
聯繫他們 上尉
Make the call, Lieutenant,
為了布魯塔星雲和太空
for the sake of the Blootar Nebula and space.
艦長 太空電話接通艾戈尼亞人了
Captain, I have the Agonyans on the space-phone.
放到屏幕上
On viewer-screen.
聯盟星艦冒險號向您問好
Greetings from the USS Adventure.
我 便是這艘船的艦長
I am... the captain of this vessel,
代表整個外太空行星聯盟
representing the whole of the Alliance of Outer Space Planets.
我是茲普諾普 來自艾戈尼亞三元帝國
I am Zipnop of the Triathic Agonyan Empire.
崇拜我們吧 渺小可悲的人類糧堆
All worship to us, small, pathetic, human food-piles.
我們在布魯塔星雲裡檢測到了
We scanned an unusual level of radiation
水平異常的輻射
in the Blootar Nebula.
儘管這是在貴國的管轄區外
Even though this is outside of your empire's... jurisdiction.
好一個彌天大謊
That is a lie!
可悲卻美味的人類們四散的謠言
Spread by pathetic but delicious humans.
但是 醫生
And yet... Doctor,
我們的船上不是出現了大量的
have we not received multiple cases of melancholia
憂鬱症病例嗎
aboard this ship?
沒錯 艦長
We have, Cap.
憂鬱症不是只有在人類接觸到
And doesn't melancholia only occur
艾戈尼亞輻射時 才會發病嗎
when humans are exposed to Agonyan radiation waves?
的確如此
True.
將 死
Check and... mate.
啊 你發現了我們的計劃
Argh! You have figured out our plan.
就算我們需要你們的腦細胞來給輻射供能
We may need your brain cells to power our radiation,
但你們絕對阻止不了我們
but you will never stop us!
沒門 因為我們必須阻止你們
We can, and we will because we must.
這是我們星際探險家的職責
It is our duty... as space explorers.
沒機會了 我們要先滅了你
Not if we destroy you first.
我倒要看你怎麼滅
I'd like to see you try.
但是艦長 要是被他們得逞了怎麼辦
But Captain, what if they can?
你們人類有很多腦細胞
You humans are rich with brain cells.
只要你們給我們腦細胞
If you give them to us,
我們就可以不毀滅你們
we will choose not to destroy you.
給你們一分鐘的時間
You have one minute to
來滿足我們的要求
comply with our wishes.
艾戈尼亞人把我們逼上了絕路
The Agonyans have put us in an impossible situation.
只剩一條出路了
There is... only one solution.
絕不能給出我們的腦細胞
We can't give them our brain cells.
從科學角度講 我們需要腦細胞
We need it... for many science reasons.
艦長 艾戈尼亞人
Captain, the Agonyans
正在向我們發射核能激光
are firing a series of nuclear lasers at us.
升起護盾 準備迎接衝擊
Shields up! Brace for impact!
用光子射線還擊
Fire photonos beams at them!
他們走了
They're gone.
隨之而去的還有
And so is...
-我們的腦細胞 -不
- our brain cells. - No!
我們怎麼辦
What do we do?
首先 我們找到艾戈尼亞人
First... we find the Agonyans...
拿回我們的腦細胞
...retrieve our... brain cells,
然後
and then...
找回我們的快樂
we get back our joy.
銀河系 人類最後的邊疆
Galaxies: the last frontier.
這是聯盟星艦冒險號的故事
This is the tale of the USS Adventure
她長達八十四個月的任務
on its 84-month mission
去迷航至宇宙最遙遠的角落
as it treks across the furthest reaches of the universe,
去努力尋找未知生命
striving to find unknown life,
未解之謎 與未至之地
unexplained phenomena, and new space destinations.
勇往直前 超越極限
To go forward, to go beyond,
更勇敢地踏足更加遙遠的未竟之地
to go further and bolder than anyone ever before.
安全官日誌
Security Officer's Log.
進取號即將穿過基托利安帶
Enterprise is about to pass through the Kitolian Belt,
其環繞著的中心是一顆中子星
which centers on a neutron star.
不過在進取號研究中子星的時候
But while Enterprise studies the neutron star,
我被安排了另一項同等重要的工作
I've been assigned a separate but equally important task.
算它作雙重任務吧
Call it a dual mission.
您是想讓我去玩遊戲嗎 長官
You want me to... play a game, sir?
星際艦隊覺得他們找到了
Starfleet believes that they have figured out
能夠進行長期超光速旅行的方法
a solution to long-term, faster-than-light travel.
不用多久 星艦就可以持續巡航五年以上
Starships will soon be able to go for more
而不用中途返回聯邦
than five years without returning to Federation.
為了散心和釋放壓力
So, games and entertainment as
我們需要遊戲和娛樂
distraction and stress release.
這個我們要測試的設備是叫做
Now the device we're going to be testing is called
「娛樂室」
the "Re-creation Room"?
簡稱 全息甲板
Holodeck, for short.
-這個好聽 -沒錯
- Sounds better. - Yeah.
這東西是基於戰鬥模擬器改進的嗎
Is this based on battle simulators?
畢竟 模擬器每一關我全都打過了
'Cause I-I've beaten every one of those.
不然為什麼我們選你呢
Why do you think we picked you?
但是這種模擬器通常都設在星站上
But those simulators are usually on starbases.
它會占用大量的能量和算力
They take up huge amounts of energy and processing power.
我們的船真的撐得起來嗎
Can our ship actually handle it?
我們就是來搞明白這一點的
That's what we're here to figure out.
我們的命令很明確
Our orders are clear.
在進取號研究坍縮中子星的同時
While Enterprise studies the collapsing neutron star,
你要來測試全息甲板
you're going to test the holodeck.
實戰測試一下它能不能在出任務時啟用
Put it through its paces under a real mission.
證明它能在真實的 嚴苛的環境下運作
Show it could work under genuine, rigorous circumstances.
您覺得一場遊戲對全息甲板來說能有多嚴苛 長官
How rigorous do you expect a game on the holodeck to be, sir?
嘛 這是個測試 上尉
Well, it's a test, Lieutenant.
我以前當試飛員的時候
The kind of thing I'd do all the time
對測試只有一種態度
when I was a test pilot.
意思就是
Which means,
往死裡測試它
you push it as hard as you can.
你跟我說過你想要點挑戰
You told me you needed a challenge.
不用謝
You're welcome.
我打擾你了嗎
Am I interrupting?
我選擇用舞蹈訓練代替
In lieu of my normal morning calisthenics,
我每天早上的體操運動
I have elected to continue dance training.
已經差不多要結束了
I have nearly completed my routine.
噢 我來了你也不用停啊
Oh, don't stop on my account.
計算機 播放歌單 史波克十九號
Computer, begin playlist: Spock 19.
探戈
Tango.
很上進啊
Ambitious.
我只是順道來問一下 斯考提讓你修的
I just swung by to ask about the field emitters
全息甲板力場發射器現在怎麼樣了
for the holodeck that you've been fixing for Scotty?
抬眼 上尉
Eyes up, Lieutenant.
你之前對我說 眼神是探戈生根的地方
You told me the eyes are the anchor of the tango.
不是嗎
Are they not?
我的診斷分析差不多都完成了
My diagnostics are nearly complete.
力場發射器都已經重新校準完畢
I have realigned the field emitters.
你和斯考特先生只要設計好程序
The holodeck should be operational as soon as you and
全息甲板即可投入運行
Mr. Scott finish designing a program for you.
謝謝
Thank you.
戴著監控針會讓你難受嗎
Has the monitoring pin been much of a burden?
我都忘了自己還戴著這東西
I actually forgot I was wearing it.
這是好事
That is a good thing.
能捕捉到你自然的狀態是最好的
It is best if it captures you in a natural state,
這樣全息甲板就能根據你的參數
so the holodeck can construct the most realistic environment
營造出最逼真的環境
for your specifications.
說到這裡 你選好全息模擬的主題了嗎
Speaking of, have you chosen a subject for your simulation?
還沒呢
Not yet.
我對人類娛樂領域涉獵未深
I am not well-versed in human entertainment,
不過暴力與休閒的主題似乎比較熱門
but violence and relaxation seem to be popular.
此外
Along with...
浪漫故事亦是如此
...romantic narratives.
艾米莉亞
Amelia.
《艾米莉亞·穆恩》是什麼鬼
Amelia Moon? What the hell is that?
20世紀60年代的地球偵探小說
Detective stories from Earth in the 1960s.
那位把我從戈恩人手裡救出來的艦長
The-the captain of the ship that rescued me from the Gorn--
給了我一本
he-he gave me a copy,
看得我愛不釋手
and I became obsessed.
艾米莉亞是個局外人 但她總是莫名地
Amelia was an outsider, but she always found herself
被捲入各種謀殺案 綁架案
in the middle of a murder, or a kidnapping,
或者鬧了什麼烏龍的搶劫案
or a heist gone wrong.
但她總是能伸張正義
And she always got justice,
無論情況如何
no matter what.
這麼說吧
Let's just say...
我被她帶壞了
she had an effect on me.
數據庫裡找到了112項結果
There are 112 of them in the database.
這些內容拿來建立模擬綽綽有餘了
That's plenty of material to form the simulation.
不過要讓模擬就這麼一直運行下去
Although, the computer might have trouble
計算機會有點吃力
keeping the simulation running as it is.
考慮到佩利亞離艦休假了
Uh, Pelia's on shore leave,
所以你的意思是 又要請史波克出馬了
so, you-you want to call in Spock again?
小事一樁 我搞得定
It's nothing I can't handle.
我能把全艦其他系統
I-I can balance the processing needs
的處理需求給勻過來
from the rest of the ship.
不過 有個小問題
Although, there is one wee wrinkle.
呃 全息投影的角色
Uh, the holographic characters
必須做到纖毫畢現才夠格
need to be incredibly detailed to pass muster.
分辨率這麼高的生命特徵數據
The only bio-signatures we have at that resolution
我們只在傳送器模式緩衝區裡有
are from the transporter pattern buffer.
我們會利用他們的形象
We'll use their likenesses
來創造全息可交互角色
to create holographic interactive avatars.
就等你準備好了 上尉
Ready when you are, Lieutenant.
計算機 以艾米莉亞·穆恩系列小說為參考
Computer: using the Amelia Moon novels as reference
並根據我自身的偵探水平
and factoring in my skills as an investigator,
創造一個我難以解決的懸疑故事
create a new mystery that I will find challenging to solve.
史波克 我
Spock, I...
我以為你已經完成診斷分析了
I thought you'd finished running diagnostics.
我想確保計算機系統能在
I wanted to ensure the computer system is functioning
正常參數內運行
at normal parameters.
多謝你的關心
I appreciate your concern.
但是 不要告訴斯考提
But, uh, don't tell Scotty.
他為了這事忙得累死累活的
He's been working very hard on this.
確實 他很敏感
Indeed. He is sensitive.
你隨時都可啟動並評估該程序
You may run and evaluate the program on your command.
計算機
Computer:
運行程序
...run program.
我能真的聞到大海和香煙的味道
I can practically smell the ocean and the cigarettes.
在全息甲板的有限空間內吸煙並非明智之舉
It would be unwise to smoke in the confines of the holodeck.
或者說 吸煙本就不明智
Or at all.
不 我只是覺得這 這真是太
No. I just meant it's-it's very, um...
栩栩如生
Lifelike.
確實如此
Indeed.
我讀了那麼久的艾米莉亞啊 我只是
I have spent so many hours reading about Amelia. I just...
我不敢相信我真的能親身扮演她
I just can't believe I actually get to be her.
好吧 正如我的祖先
Well, as my ancestor,
阿瑟·柯南·道爾爵士會寫的那樣
Sir Arthur Conan Doyle would write,
「遊戲開始了」
"The game is afoot."
謝謝 史波克先生
Thank you, Mr. Spock,
但這是個單人檔
but this is a single-player situation.
隨時為你效勞
I am available,
需要我的幫助就隨時叫我
should you decide you need my assistance.
祝你好運 上尉
Good luck, Lieutenant.
艾米莉亞·穆恩
Amelia Moon!
-謝天謝地你來了 -烏乎拉
- Thank goodness you're here. - Uhura.
喬尼·格洛斯 我們在去年十一月
Joni Gloss. We met briefly
你解決那起福克斯慘案的時候有過一面之緣
when you handled that Fox fiasco last November.
你保住了我的客戶的事業
Saved my client's career,
才讓他沒被關進聖昆汀監獄
and kept him out of San Quentin.
好了 跟我來
Now, follow me.
是我發現了屍體
I'm the one who found the body.
不是我還能是誰
Of course, I did.
我總是第一個到
I'm always the first to arrive.
在這座城裡我有條規矩
And I have a rule in this town.
如果你準時 那你就遲到了
If you're on time, you're late.
如果你遲到了 你就死定了
And if you're late, you're dead.
現在好了 真的死人了
In this case, literally.
當然 這可不是我幹的
Not by my hand, of course.
你會記下這句話的吧
You'll put that in your record?
不過 你不是第一個到的客人 對吧
Only, you weren't the first guest to arrive, were you?
他們當中有一個人殺了托尼
One of them killed Tony,
我只是不知道是誰
I just don't know who.
所以我就聯繫你了
That's why I called you.
我需要你在條子趕來之前
I need you to solve this
解決這個案子
before the cops show up.
不然他們就會把我們所有人都抓起來
They will arrest every one of us
只是為了把故事賣給那些八卦小報
just to sell the story to the gossip rags,
接著轉眼間 你還沒反應過來呢
and then, poof, before you know it,
我一半的客戶都被炒魷魚了
half my clients, out of a job.
所以我要保護好你的客戶
So, protect your clients.
當然啦 除了兇手
Except the murderer, obviously.
我要跟那傢伙解約
I'm going to drop them.
屍體在哪裡
Where's the body?
在這裡
In there.
說實話
Staying honest,
我幾乎不敢看他
I could barely look at him.
我會在客廳裡拖住其他人
I'll stall the others in the sitting room
你儘管去做你該做的事
while you go do what it is you... do.
有火嗎
Got a light?
真棒
Fantastic.
加州 好萊塢
Hollywood, California.
豪宅 影星
Mansions, movie stars,
和命案
and murder.
窒息性死亡
Strangulation.
但兇器是什麼
But with what?
在今晚九點鐘
At 9:00 p.m. tonight,
托尼·哈特
Tony Hart,
洛蒙德電影製片廠負責人
head of Lomond Picture Studios
在家中被人勒死
was strangled in his own home.
然而兇器未知
But with what?
兇手未知
And by whom?
千萬別忘了還要查清動機
And don't forget about the "why."
找到殺人動機
Find your motive,
你就能找到兇手
and you've got your killer.
一般來說 動機都悄悄地
Usually, a motive hides
藏在陰影之下
quiet secrets hidden in shadows
藏在緊閉的門後
and behind closed doors,
但我能看出這案子的要素十分齊全
but I could see this case had it all.
激情 絕望
Passion, desperation,
嫉妒 暴怒
jealousy, rage.
至於這些嫌疑犯嘛
And as for the suspects,
有些人你估計看著還眼熟
you may recognize some of the guests
洛蒙德電視台的太空冒險時間檔
from Lomond's television space adventure hour,
《星際邊疆》的組員
The Last Frontier,
例如該節目的主創 TK·貝洛斯
including the show's creator TK Bellows
以及曾是演員 後來成為製片人的 桑尼·盧皮諾
and former actress turned producer Sunny Lupino.
該劇的大明星 阿德萊德·肖
The show's stars-- Adelaide Shaw,
麥克斯韋·聖和李·伍茲也在這裡
Maxwell Saint and Lee Woods-- are also here,
還有肖的心頭肉 安東尼·麥克比奧
along with Shaw's main squeeze, Anthony MacBeau.
而你已經見過頂級經紀人喬尼·格洛斯了
And you already met power agent Joni Gloss.
這場聚會的東家 托尼·哈特死了
Your host, Tony Hart, is dead,
而兇手就是你們之中的某人
and one of you murdered him.
先別急 等一下
Hold your horses.
我們這裡為什麼會有人想謀殺哈特
Why would one of us want to murder Hart?
因為你的節目就要被砍了
Because your show was about to be canceled.
開玩笑 我們可是大熱門啊
Canceled? But we're a hit.
哦 收視率
Oh. Ratings.
好了 接下來
Now, here's how this is going to go.
任何人都不許從那扇門出去
No one is gonna walk out of that door
也不能打電話
or make any phone calls.
你也不行 威廉·莫里斯
Even you, William Morris.
我們得好好待在一起
We're all gonna get real cozy
直到把這一切都弄清楚
until we've worked this all out.
這種事不該發生在我頭上啊
This can't be happening. To me.
目前已知的信息有
What we know:
今晚九點 有人用不明武器
At 9:00 p.m. tonight, someone strangled Tony Hart
在臥室中勒死了托尼·哈特
with an unknown weapon in his bedroom.
我們知道兇手就在這個房間裡
We know the killer is in this room,
而且我們知道 動機很可能是因為
and we know the likely motive is the cancelation
《星際邊疆》要被砍了
of The Last Frontier.
而解開這個謎題的關鍵
And the key to this puzzle...
像玻璃般清晰明了
...is as clear as glass.
什麼
What?
等等 不是 不是我幹的
Wait, it wasn't... it wasn't me.
大家都知道你喝的是什麼 朋友
Everyone knows your drink, pal.
我相信你
I believe you.
此外 你更喜歡偏冷色調的粉色
Besides, you favor a frostier shade of pink.
但這款色可是經典的
But this shade is classic.
蜜絲佛陀的紅寶石紅
Max Factor's Ruby Red,
1955年發售 並在各大
released in 1955, and splashed
時尚雜誌上大肆宣傳
all over fashion magazines
就塗在這位模特兼流行歌星標誌性的嘴唇上
on the iconic face of model and pop star
正是桑尼·盧皮諾
Sunny Lupino.
不然呢 我可是引領潮流的巨星
What can I say, I'm a trendsetter.
但這證明不了我就是兇手
But that doesn't make me a killer.
確實不行
That doesn't.
但這個可以
But this does.
《星際邊疆》是你身為製片人出品的第一個項目
The Last Frontier was your first project as a producer.
你拚命爭取讓它成功播出
You fought to get it on the air,
從你跟工作室的關係 到你的前夫
leveraged your relationships with the studio
全都是大好的資源
and your ex-husband.
你把你的整個職業生涯都押上去了
Bet your whole career on it.
托尼和我是離婚了
Tony and I were divorced,
但我們在工作方面一直都是互利互助
but we were still very much invested in each other's success.
你的投入比絕大多數人都多 不是嗎
You were a little more invested than most, weren't you?
想把太空劇帶進美國家庭的客廳可是很燒錢的 所以
It's expensive to bring space into American living rooms, so
你私下借了筆貸款
you took a personal loan from...
借黑幫的錢 但要是劇被砍了的話
...the mob. But if the show was canceled,
你就沒法償還這筆債務了 於是
you'd never be able to pay it back, so...
你殺了托尼以求這部劇能繼續播出
...you killed Tony to keep it on the air.
關於此人我只知道一件事 他是我的粉絲
The only thing I know about that man is that he's a fan.
來找我要簽名的
He wanted an autograph.
那又何必用長焦鏡頭呢
Why the telelens, then?
我當時在佩里諾飯店跟約翰尼享用晚餐
I was having dinner at Perino's with Johnny.
那人姓卡森 想讓我參與一個全國廣播公司的項目
Carson. He was trying to talk me into a project at NBC.
托尼一直都在監視我
Tony was keeping tabs on me
想確保我沒有跟別人勾搭上
to make sure I wasn't being unfaithful.
以防我想背後坑製片廠
To the studio.
但你說對了
But you're right.
我確實有做自己的投資
I did invest my own money,
但錢不是從黑幫借來的
I just didn't take it from the mob.
我把房子賣了
I sold the house.
我和托尼的第一個房子
Mine and Tony's first house.
啊 你不是可喜歡那間房子了嗎
Oh, but you love that house.
在說服艾爾弗雷德讓我出演《烏鴉》之前
Until I convinced Alfred to put me in Crows,
我還只是個無名小卒
I was just another pair of lips.
但奧斯卡獎一到手 機會來了
But that Oscar opened doors.
機會到手之後我幹什麼了 去買豪車嗎
And what did I use it for, my own star vehicles?
我沒有 我聽到TK在推銷
No. When I heard TK's pitch
他的《星際邊疆》
for The Last Frontier,
那一刻我就意識到 這部劇可不一般
I knew it was special.
只要能拯救它 你做什麼都願意
And you'd do anything to save it.
那不是廢話
You're damn right, I would.
我甚至找托尼商量我的計劃
I even came to Tony with a plan.
-但他拒絕了 -他同意了
- But he refused. - He agreed.
我們還在商討細節呢
We were going over the details
結果聊了一半被麥克斯韋·聖打斷了
when Maxwell Saint interrupted us.
假如你真想知道
If you really want to know
托尼到底怎麼了
what happened to Tony,
問他去
talk to him.
天哪
Oh, my God.
李 她死了嗎
Lee? Is she dead?
你知道我是個演員 不是醫生吧
You know I'm an actor, not a doctor, right?
但是你看她這模樣
But, yeah. I mean, look at her.
怎麼看都是死了
She's obviously dead.
死於中毒
Poison.
斯考提 你在忙嗎
Scotty, you busy?
有點忙
A bit busy, yeah.
你的模擬程序能耗有點超標 咋了
Your simulation is pulling a wee bit more power than expected. Why?
以戰鬥模擬器為原型開發的全息甲板
Base a holodeck on a battle simulator
反應也會和戰鬥模擬器一樣
and it's going to act like one.
什麼意思
What does that mean?
它看穿我了 預判了我的行動
Well, it's figured me out, learned my moves.
好像真的是我的敵人一樣
Just like an enemy opponent.
這種設置怎麼改
Well, how can I change that?
不用改 我需要換個視角
No, I need a fresh eye,
找一個和我思維不同的人來
someone who won't see things like I do.
在第57本書《紙月旅館謀殺案》裡面
In book number 57, Murder at the Paper Moon Inn,
艾米莉亞·穆恩找了一個搭檔
Amelia Moon needed a partner.
這個嘛 恐怕我幫不了你
Well, I'm afraid it can't be me
沒了我進取號要停擺的
if you want the Enterprise to continue running.
噢 沒事
Oh, no, that's okay.
我覺得我已經有個完美的舞伴了
I think I might have the perfect dance partner already.
史波克  多謝你來幫我
Spock, thank you for coming.
我會盡力給你提供全面的幫助
I'm here to assist in any way I can.
不過 我有一事想問
Though, may I ask,
既然你已經輸給了全息甲板的程序
if the holodeck has defeated you,
為何不直接結束任務呢
why not just end the mission?
聽著 派克艦長給了我很明確的命令
Look, Pike gave me very clear orders:
要用嚴苛的條件來測試這個設備
Test the device under rigorous circumstances.
以及 我還沒輸呢 是我升級了
Also, it didn't defeat me, I leveled up
然後它提高了難度
and then it increased the difficulty.
再說了
Besides,
艾米莉亞·穆恩在抓到兇手前絕不放棄
Amelia Moon doesn't give up until she gets her man,
我也一樣
and neither do I.
我已經大致了解了案件
I have briefed myself on the case.
偵探穆恩的搭檔是什麼樣的
What was Detective Moon's partner like?
想來應當是個好手
Proficient, I assume?
他是個笨手笨腳的傻子
He was a bumbling idiot.
-聽起來沒什麼用處 -確實
- That does not seem useful. - No.
但你的用處可大多了
You will be much more so.
這是誰啊
Who's this guy?
史波克偵探
Detective Spock.
我的同事
He works with me.
他怎麼穿得跟來參加睡衣派對一樣
I didn't know this was a pajama party.
等等
Hang on.
是演員分配部派你來的嗎
Did Central Casting send you?
就他那耳朵 開玩笑的吧
What, with those ears?
史波克偵探不看電視
Detective Spock doesn't watch television.
合著這哥們是共產黨嗎
So he's a communist?
更像那種愛看電影的文藝逼
More likely one of those cinema snobs.
這有什麼關係
What does it matter?
全息柯克似乎情緒很激動
The holo-Kirk seems particularly agitated.
正常 他可是我的頭號嫌犯
He should, he's number one on my suspect list.
辛苦你趕過來了
Thanks for coming so fast.
看看這些波動
These fluctuations... here.
它們變得越發頻繁了
They're becoming more frequent.
考慮到那顆坍塌中的中子星只有六小時航程遠
We are six hours from a collapsing star.
有一些小波動是正常的
Minor surges are to be expected.
大家全在通宵工作
Everyone's pulling an all-nighter.
我甚至跟派克建議讓奧特加斯復職
I even recommended Pike reinstate Ortegas.
你信任她嗎
And you trust her?
當然
I do.
輔助能源貌似也出現了些問題
Auxiliary power also seems to be having issues.
這應該不在標準情況之下了
This seems beyond standard.
別擔心 一切都在掌控之中
Don't worry, I've got everything under control.
傳感器嚴重過載 電容電力故障 全息二極管分析中
哇 這傳感器過載得太誇張了吧
Wow, that is a sensory overload.
噢都是正常的 都在掌控之中
Oh, all normal, all under control.
全向全息二極管產生的變量
The omnidirectional holo-diodes produce
實在是太多了 不太好全都關照到
a tremendous number of variables to keep an eye on.
需要找個人幫你嗎
Do you need a second set of eyes?
沒事 我能搞定
No, I've got it.
以我的經驗看 有時候多一個人
In my experience, sometimes a second set of eyes
可能會適得其反 我能搞定的
can be... detrimental. I-I can handle it.
好的 但我需要先簽收你的工程日誌
Okay, but I do need to sign off on your engineering logs
然後再回去處理中子星的事
before returning to work on the neutron star.
祝你能夠打破之前那位總管留下的
Fingers crossed you improve upon the haphazard example
一團亂麻的先例
set by your... supervisor.
是的 我知道佩利亞的日誌實在是
Yes, I'm familiar with, uh,
臭名昭著
Pelia's infamous logs.
老鷹都能把眼睛看瞎
An eagle could go blind from reading them.
-這就撐不住了嗎 -沒有沒有
- Broken already? - Oh, no, no.
小毛病 在測試階段很正常
Just a wee bug, to be expected with
不用大驚小怪
beta phase testing.
這模擬器畢竟這麼大 它會自動調取
You know, a simulator this big will automatically pull
算力來進行補償 你明白的
processing power to compensate, but, you know,
這算不上啥問題
it's not a problem.
只要轉移一些能量 沒事啦
I'll just, um, divert a little juice. Yeah.
雖說拉安是在實地親力親為的那個
La'An may be running this test,
不過
but, uh,
堅強的後盾可是你啊
you're the failsafe.
明白明白
Understood. Loud and clear.
我一定能搞定噠
But, you know, I've got it.
聖先生 是你殺了托尼·哈特和桑尼·盧皮諾嗎
Mr. Saint, did you kill Tony Hart and Sunny Lupino?
不是
Nope.
是你嗎
Did you?
桑尼說 托尼死之前
Sonny said you and Tony
你和他在吵架
were fighting before he died.
小打小鬧罷了
A tiff. A row.
退一萬步說 吵了兩句吧
A tangle, maybe.
沒啥好搬出來講的
It's not even worth discussing.
不過是因為有人嫉妒了
It was jealousy.
嫉妒
Jealousy?
你的手鐲
Your cuff.
在作案現場有一個一模一樣的
There was an identical one at the crime scene.
這是哈特的秘書送我的廉價小玩意
A little trinket from Hart's secretary.
她喜歡我
She likes me.
你們在搞外遇
You were having an affair.
被你發現了
You caught me.
哈特先生對此有意見 是吧
And Mr. Hart had an issue with this?
剛巧只是因為他在和同一位秘書搞外遇啦
Well, only because he was having an affair with the same secretary.
聽起來很複雜
sounds complicated.
並沒有 隨便玩玩罷了
No, not really. It was casual.
人與人之間一旦開始緊密合作
You work closely with people,
奇妙的事情自然會發生
and things happen.
想必二位一定深有感觸
You two must know how that goes.
什麼 我們
What? We--
沒有 這是你的事
No, this-this is about you,
與別人無關
not... anyone else.
聽著 我是一個演員
Look, I'm an actor.
我喜歡演戲
I like drama,
但絕對沒必要出於這種理由殺人
but it's certainly nothing to kill for.
另外 我早騙過了哈特
And besides, I had already convinced Hart that
跟他說我與那位秘書分手了
it was over between me and the secretary.
他怎麼就信你了
And how did you do that?
我和麥克斯韋鬼混嗎
Me and Maxwell?
絕對百分百沒門
Absolutely 100% never.
你好像情緒很激動啊
You seem awfully heated about that.
他是個極端大男子主義的自大狂
He's a chauvinistic egomaniac.
光是跟他待在同一個布景裡我都忍不了
I can barely stand to be on set with the guy.
我跟他上床圖啥啊
Why would I go to bed with him?
你知不知道這部劇要被砍了
Were you aware that the show was being cancelled?
知道些小道消息
I heard whispers.
你對此有什麼想法
How did you feel about it?
這個嘛
Well,
我的台詞和裙子
my lines and my skirts have been
越往後拍越短
getting shorter and shorter with every episode,
唯一一個
and the only person
為我的角色爭取權利的就是桑尼
who ever fought for my character was Sunny.
現在她也死了
And now she's dead, so...
你知道我在西區出演海達·高布樂時
Did you know that I was just 18 when I played
才十八歲嗎
Hedda Gabler on the West End?
二位偵探 我是個好演員
I'm good at what I do, Detectives.
但別人似乎只關心你的感情生活如何
But all anyone seems to care about is your love life.
肯定很令人沮喪吧
Must be frustrating.
是啊 很沮喪
Yeah, it is.
我只是想要在職業生涯中
But is it wrong to want love
兼顧愛情和我應得的尊重 這有什麼錯嗎
and to be taken seriously in my career?
那你覺得 為什麼你和聖先生
So, why do you think there are persistent rumors
之間的流言總是屢次三番地被提起呢
about your affair with Mr. Saint?
你覺得盧皮諾小姐是個什麼樣的人
How did you feel about Miss Lupino?
你是說 我有沒有殺她的動機
You mean, did I have a reason to kill her?
沒有
No.
我敬佩她
I admired her.
她不願意只做一個花瓶
She couldn't settle for being a work of art.
她想要成為藝術的創作人
She wanted to make art.
你對藝術很看重啊
Art means a lot to you.
藝術就是一切
It's everything.
如果說我想要贈給世人什麼禮物
If I can give a gift to the world,
那就是幫助人們解放
I want to help people unleash
心中那頭藝術的野獸
the artistic beast inside of them.
怎麼解放你這所謂的藝術野獸
How does one "unleash the artistic beast"?
我一直在辦一個藝術家沙龍
I've been doing an artists salon.
李之前可能和你們講過了
Lee probably told you about it.
具體陳述一下沙龍的活動
What goes on at an artists salon?
麥克彈吉他
Mac plays guitar.
其他人有的唱歌 有的畫畫
Others sing, paint.
你呢
And you?
李寫些東西
Lee writes.
確切地說 她最近在寫一部劇本
She's been writing a screenplay, actually.
電影的劇本
A movie.
什麼劇本
A screenplay?
怎麼問起這個
Why?
麥克跟你們說的嗎
Mac told you that?
在達科他州上演的一部西部片
A western set in the Dakotas.
被害人房間裡就有一本劇本
There was a script in the victim's room,
寫的是達科他州的故事
about the Dakotas.
還有誰知道劇本的事
Who else knew about this?
打算畏罪潛逃哈
Guilty conscience got you running?
不是畏罪 是胃病
More like a weak stomach.
多年心血付之東流
Must be hard to watch something you've poured so much into
很難受吧
just disappear.
心裡確實是疙疙瘩瘩的
It's not my favorite feeling, no.
是不是收視率太低了 不能續訂第二季
But the ratings were too low to warrant a season two?
粉絲雖然不多 但還是充滿熱情的嘛
Our fanbase is small, but it's quite passionate.
伍茲小姐的西部電影
Were you threatened
有沒有讓你感到受威脅
by the Western motion picture Miss Woods wrote?
李又寫了一部西部片嗎 挺好的
Lee wrote another Western? Good for her.
她就喜歡吊死在這種早過時了的題材上
She'll never tire of that dying genre.
所以 你知道劇本的事
So, you knew about the script?
不覺得嫉妒嗎
You weren't jealous?
談談電視劇被砍的事吧
What about the cancellation?
這也是你之前就知道的嗎
Did you know about that, too?
於是你就撕合同了 衝冠一怒 是嗎
Is that why you ripped up your contract? Out of anger?
你知道他們是怎麼評價第一季的嗎
Do you know what they say about a show after its first season?
不知道 說說看吧
No. What do they say?
有一種沒過腦子的美感
Practically writes itself.
哈特撕的合同 不是我
Hart ripped up that contract, not me.
真是幫了我個忙
He was actually doing me a favor.
你早就想離開節目了嗎
You wanted to leave the show?
有本我中意已久的書 版權在華納兄弟公司手裡
Warners has the rights to a book I've been chasing.
他們甚至同意讓我來執導了
They're even gonna let me direct.
是啊 我真心喜歡這部劇
Yeah, I-I-I love our show,
但那可是電影啊
but movies...
電影才能真正改造人的靈魂 孩子們
That's how you change hearts and minds, kids.
這麼說來 劇被砍了你還挺開心的
So, you're happy the show was being canceled?
偵探大人
Oh, Detective.
我是作家
I'm a writer.
我對什麼事都高興不起來
I'm never happy about anything.
但我沒殺人
But I didn't kill anyone.
他們身為同事
They all worked together,
卻任由私人情緒泛濫
yet allowed their emotions to jeopardize
妨礙了共同的工作
the very work that they all shared.
這是什麼
What is that?
李·伍茲的劇本
Lee Woods's script.
我就知道有什麼不對勁
I knew something was off about it.
看 沒封面
Look, no title page.
為什麼呢
But why?
也許是為了隱去劇本的作者
Perhaps to hide the connection to the writer.
不 不是貝洛斯幹的 他不在乎這個
No, no, no, not from Bellows. He didn't even care.
不對
No.
有沒有可能 不是李撕掉的
What if Lee's not the one who removed it?
拉安
La'An...
看起來吊燈是
The chandelier appears to have been
被故意切斷來傷害我們的
purposefully cut to harm us.
為了阻止我們
To stop us
因為我們已經靠近真相了
because we're close.
劇本沒有封面
The screenplay doesn't have a title page
是因為劇本被人偷走了
because it was stolen.
哈特偷了李的劇本 把作者改成其他人
Hart stole Lee's script and was going to credit someone else,
也許是想歸功給某個男的 那個年代常有這種事
probably a man, because that happened all the time back then.
於是她就把哈特殺了
So she killed him for it.
有更要緊的事
There is a more pressing matter.
怎麼有血
Blood?
我記得全息甲板不是有有安全協議的嗎
Well, I-I thought the holodeck had safety protocols.
也許是出故障了
Perhaps they are malfunctioning.
我們得離開這裡 不要冒險
We should get out of here, not risk anything else.
計算機 終止程序
Computer, end program.
斯考特先生 把程序停下
Mr. Scott, please end program.
計算機 顯示拱門
Computer, arch.
這下
So...
我們關不掉它了
we can't shut it off,
而且程序真的能傷害我們
the program could actually hurt us,
我們還出不去
and we can't get out.
正是如此
Indeed.
斯考特中尉 你在找我嗎
Lieutenant Scott, are you looking for me?
這樣 假設一下我們出了點通訊故障
Say I've got this hypothetical communications problem,
你能不能給我點指導 像往常一樣
could you advise me on this problem that, again,
我是說假設哈 並不是真出了亂子
you know, it's not a real problem,
你不要按字面意思理解這個詞
in the traditional sense of the word "problem."
我大概明白你的意思
I think I followed that.
假設有一種非常小概率的事件發生了
In the highly unlikely event
就是說呢 我和全息甲板裡的拉安徹底失聯了
that I were to have lost all contact with La'An inside the holodeck,
你的建議是什麼
what would you advise?
如果失聯的話
Well, if comms failed,
我會繞過局部子處理器
I'd bypass local subprocessors
直接聯通光電數據網絡
and patch directly into the optical data network.
好 我們再假設一下
Yeah. Imagine in this hypothetical,
我已經這樣嘗試了若干次
like, I've already done that, multiple times.
假設說來 我會去直接關閉模擬
Hypothetically, I'd shut the simulation down.
現在看來 我估計你
Which, I'm assuming,
在假設條件下 已經試過了
you've already, hypothetically, done.
斯考提啊 你是說拉安被困在全息甲板裡了嗎
Scotty, are you telling me La'An is trapped in the holodeck?
你要不試試 敲敲門
Have you tried knocking on the door?
或者把門炸了
Or simply blowing it off?
全息甲板裡面的各類力場 牽引光束還有高精度二極管
The holodeck is a complex balance of forcefields, tractor beams,
之間的平衡極為複雜
and precision-guided diodes,
而且設備全都直連主機
all hardwired in.
所以炸門會癱瘓整個計算機系統
So, blowing it up would crash our entire computer system.
修不好的那種 經過我的計算
Permanently. Per my calculations,
除非拉安上尉走完程序的流程
the only way to unlock the program
沒有其他辦法解除程序鎖定
is for the lieutenant to complete it,
但她完全不知情
but she's unaware of this.
怎麼樣才能走完流程
What does completing it entail?
破一樁一九六九年的好萊塢謀殺案
Solving a murder mystery set in 1969 Hollywood.
我會幫你的
I'm on it.
謝謝你 少尉
Thank you, Ensign.
你知道這都不是假設吧
you-you know that wasn't all hypothetical?
是啊 你剛開口我就知道了
Yeah, I caught on almost immediately.
好的
Okay.
很不幸 在模擬程序裡
Unfortunately, I was unable to access the panel
各面板無法響應
while in the simulation.
我還是聯絡不上斯考特或是艦上的任何人
I still can't reach Scotty over comms or anyone on the ship.
所以我們既有計算機問題
So, we have a computer problem
又有通訊問題
and a communications problem.
別忘了還有謀殺案
We also have a murderer problem.
如果殺手要對我們動手 我們真的會死
If the killer comes after us, we could actually die in here.
所以也許唯一的活路是抓出兇手
So maybe the only way to survive is to catch the murderer.
也就是說
Which means...
得把案子徹底破掉
we're going to go solve this mystery.
我只是
I-I just...
無法相信你想離開劇組
can't believe you wanted off the show.
你不是也想離開嗎
You also wanted off the show.
你猜怎麼著 我看你就是恨我
You know what I think? I think you hate me,
還恨我給了你這輩子
and you hate the fact that I gave you the best job
能接到的最好的工作
that you're ever gonna have.
你在威脅我嗎
Are you threatening me?
都聽見了吧
Did you all hear that?
TK在威脅我
TK threatened me!
他講的是實話
He tells no lies.
你又懂上了
What would you know?
你只是給阿德萊德當跑路的下家的
You're only here as Adelaide's escape hatch.
你這又什麼意思呢
What is that supposed to mean?
觀眾不喜歡你
Audiences don't like you.
至少我懂怎麼正常地念台詞
At least I can deliver a line realistically.
我那叫表演
It's called acting.
你知道什麼才是不正常的嗎
And you know what's not realistic?
一個女大副
A lady first officer.
承認現實吧 你早就明白自己沒什麼前途
Face it. You knew your days were limited.
於是你才嫁了這個搖滾巨星
That's why you agreed to marry Mick Bowie over here,
做他的小迷妹 跟著他演出就不顯眼了
so you could disappear on tour as his groupie
就沒人會注意到你的職業生涯早完蛋了
and nobody would notice that your career was dead!
你們都給我閉嘴
Everyone shut up, now!
好了
Right.
李·伍茲去哪兒了
Where is Lee Woods?
這個睡衣男到底是哪兒冒出來的
And who is this guy?
她死了
She's dead.
喬尼·格洛斯
Joni Gloss.
不是這樣的 你誤會了
It's not what it looks like.
我只想是來借個火
I was just looking for a light.
我找到她時她就已經死了
She was dead when I found her.
星際邊疆這部劇要是被砍
You had quite a bit of cash to lose
你的經濟損失應該會不小吧
from the cancelation of The Last Frontier, didn't you?
我在節目裡有三個客戶 你算算損失大不大
I had three clients on that show. You do the math.
但我沒殺托尼·哈特
But I didn't kill Tony Hart,
雖說我恨不得殺了他
though I wish I had.
為什麼
And why is that?
因為砍掉《星際邊疆》
Because canceling The Last Frontier
是托尼做過的最蠢的事
is the stupidest thing Tony's ever done.
你知道這樣的一部劇有多難得嗎
Do you realize how rare a show like this is?
TK想要做的是通過科幻世界
TK wanted to give audiences a digestible reflection
來給觀眾們呈現他們能看懂的 關於現實世界的反思
of their own world through the lens of fantasy.
通過外星人的橡膠頭套與故事情節中的隱喻
Social commentary with rubber masks
給出社會評論 科幻嘛 就是這樣的
and buried metaphors. You know, science fiction.
公司反對他的遠大圖景 是嗎
And the studio did not agree with this vision?
他們更傾向於
They were more...
謹言慎行
cautious.
不願意在社會上掀起波瀾 這幫懦夫
Didn't want to "make waves." The cowards.
TK希望星際邊疆能取代這個腐爛的世界
TK wanted Frontier to take our rotten world,
遠離蠅營狗苟 不仁不義
with its warts and injustices,
給觀眾一些更美好的東西
and give audiences something better.
這麼多高大上的 就憑這每週一集的太空冒險故事?
And all of that with weekly space adventures?
你不覺得這個理念很鼓舞人心嗎
You don't find the idea inspiring?
你不覺得看到這部劇的孩子們也許會
You don't think some kid out there is going to see this show
盡其餘生仰觀宇宙之大 探索星辰大海嗎
and spend the rest of their life searching the stars?
你不覺得對一個人來說
You don't think a person can love a piece of art
所深愛的藝術 又或是音樂或故事
or music or a story so much
都能夠治癒心靈嗎
that it heals them?
通過展現人們從未知曉的一部分自己
Shows them parts of themselves they'd never even seen before?
他們不會覺得看到了希望嗎
And give them hope?
呃 是這個道理
Well, no, of-of course I do.
像這樣的作品就不該有完結的一天
A show like this could've gone on forever.
它能讓一代又一代的粉絲知道
Given generations
在這裡 他們能夠被看見 感受到歸屬感
of fans a place to feel seen, to belong,
讓他們能敢於重新拾起信仰
something to believe in again,
無論他們是誰 來自什麼地方
no matter who they were or where they came from.
但要是沒有第二季 這一切都是空談
But you can't do any of that without a season two.
終於給我找到火了
Finally, a light.
假壁爐
A fake fire?
托尼對電影的品味無可挑剔
Tony had impeccable taste in film,
但他對裝飾的品味真是沒救了
but his sense of decor is just tragic.
壁爐裡是什麼
What's inside the fireplace?
賽璐珞膠片
Celluloid film.
在22世紀就停用了
Discontinued in the 22nd century,
許多人說這是電影行業的損失
many say to the detriment of cinema.
我想這就是殺人兇器
I think this is the murder weapon.
但同時也是一份記錄的載體
But it's also a recording.
這膠片裡錄有殺手想銷毀的東西
There's something on this film the killer wanted to destroy,
但他和喬尼一樣看錯了這片壁爐
but made the same mistake Joni did.
史波克 我們必須看看這裡面有什麼
Spock, we have to see what's on this.
好吧 中子星馬上要坍塌了
All right, neutron star collapse is imminent.
烏乎拉 掃描儀在收集數據了嗎
Uhura, are scanners receiving data?
正好收到 艦長
Right on time, sir.
艦長 我監測到一片伽瑪射線爆發
Captain, I'm detecting a gamma burst
正衝向我們的航行路線
heading into our flight path.
它的能量強度超乎預料地高
It's heavier energy than expected.
傳感器已經過載
The sensors are overloading.
升起護盾
Shields up.
打開黃色警報
Let's go to yellow alert.
奧特加斯 帶我們下去
Ortegas, take us down.
盡可能繞開它
Steer as clear as you can.
我也想
I'd like to,
但能量剛剛忽然被消耗了一大截
but we just had a massive power drain.
引擎無響應了
Engines aren't responding.
護盾也是
Neither are shields.
艦橋呼叫科學實驗室
Bridge to Science Lab.
斯科特先生 我們的系統怎麼了
Mr. Scott, what's happening to our system?
好吧 看起來全息甲板的能耗
Well, it seems the holodeck
還是比我預料的要多一點點
is pulling a wee bit more power than I'd anticipated.
那就把它關了
Then shut it down.
艦橋有情況 我現在就需要能量
We have a situation on the bridge, and I need power, now.
好的 但這事很複雜 艦長
Yeah, it's not quite that easy, sir.
紅色警報
Red alert.
斯科特先生
Mr. Scott,
沒有引擎動力 我們就會迎面撞進
without engine power, we are going to fly head-first into
一片巨大的伽瑪射線暴
a massive gamma-ray burst,
這樣我們無法倖免
and we are not going to survive it.
斯科特先生 我需要解決方法
Mr. Scott, I need a solution.
呃 我可以手動
Uh... I can manually
一點一點地把能量轉給你
reroute power to you in small increments.
這應該有點用
That should give you something.
快 現在就做
Do it. Do it now.
你大概有30秒的時間加速
You've got roughly 30 seconds of acceleration.
你能做到嗎
Can you make that work?
我可以一試
I do like a good challenge.
我們躲過了
We're through.
希望不要再來一次爆發了
Let's hope there isn't another one.
斯科特先生 我想跟努尼恩·辛格上尉談談
Mr. Scott, I'd like to talk to Lieutenant Noonien-Singh.
呃 我看看能否接通她
Uh, let me see if I can get her.
我們繼續假設一下
Let's say I figured out a way to contact La'An.
我找到聯絡拉安的辦法了
Hypothetically.
那你就是我的假設的英雄了
Then you'd be my hypothetical hero.
我覺得你不能用老方法聯繫她
I think you can't get through in a conventional way
因為人工智能屏蔽了所有
because the AI is blocking out all comms
模擬程序以外的通訊
that don't come from the simulation.
它拒絕讓她跟任何不是程序內的人說話
It's refusing to let her talk to anyone who's not part of the program.
它居然在進化
It's-it's... it's evolving.
所以你需要讓它相信 你也是全息投影
So you need to convince it you're a hologram, too.
太空管轄權的書
I wrote the book
可是我編的
on space jurisdiction,
而我最出名的可就是
and I am known...
語言措辭
...for my... diction.
好了
Now...
給我聯繫 艾戈尼亞人
get me... the Agonyans.
艾戈尼亞人?
The Agonyans?
-哦 停 -什麼
- Oh... cut! - What?
繼續拍 繼續拍
Keep rolling. Keep rolling.
-好的 -是不是有點過頭了
- Okay. - Was that too much? I-I...
我覺得挺好的
I thought it was great.
-我明白你的意思 -好的 好的
- I completely felt it. - Okay, okay, okay, okay.
好的 在片場安靜點
Okay. Quiet on the set.
安靜點
Quiet on the set.
又有什麼問題
What's the problem now?
哦 我該怎麼說呢
Oh, where do I even start? Uh,
要不你試試著像真正的人類一樣說台詞
maybe you could try delivering the line like an actual
哪怕就一次
human being for once?
哦
Oh.
好吧 要是你寫的台詞
Well, maybe if you wrote a line...
值得我演個正常人 我倒樂意試試
...worth delivering, I could try to.
這一幕到底講的是什麼
What is this scene even about?
不是關於資本主義的嗎
I thought it was about capitalism.
這我真沒想到
Big surprise.
你沒有理解劇本
You didn't understand the script.
這都第幾次了
Again.
這裡沒有哪怕半個人理解我的遠大圖景嗎
Does no one here care about my vision?
呃 先生
Uh, sir?
幹什麼
What?!
有你的電話 呃
There's a call. Um...
你這電話不太碰巧
Not a good time.
什麼 我
What? I...
你不能這樣 我
You can't do that. I-I...
我成就了這部劇 你不
I am the show. You c--
我
I...
你會後悔的
You'll regret this.
拉安 拉安
La'An? La'An?
拉安 我不知道你能不能看見我
La'An, I don't know if you'll see this,
但這是我唯一跟你聯繫的機會了
but it was my only chance of getting a message to you.
全息甲板把全艦其他區域的算力
The holodeck is pulling all computer
都快吸乾了
processing power from the rest of the ship.
我們阻止它的唯一方式就是終止程序
The only way to stop it is to end the program,
也就是說你得解開這個謎題
which means you have to solve the mystery.
等等 如果我們用掉了
Wait. If we're pulling all processing power,
包括護盾 導航和維生系統的所有算力
that includes shields, navigation, life support.
他們會死的 我們都會死
They could die. We could all die.
你說得很準確
An accurate assessment.
我說得很
An accurate asse...
你怎麼能一點都不關心
How are you not more concerned?
這關乎我們的朋友 我們的命
These are our friends, our lives.
你要求我保持客觀冷靜
You asked me to remain detached.
我只是按你的要求行事
I am merely doing as you requested.
我們現在知道貝洛斯確實非常在乎
We now know that Bellows did indeed care very much
劇集被砍的事
about the cancellation.
對 這給了他動機 並且他有機會動手
Yep. That gives him motive, and he had an opportunity.
但他沒理由殺伍茲或者盧皮諾
But he had no reason to kill Woods or Lupino.
她可沒砍這部劇
She didn't cancel the show.
她願意付出一切來拯救它
She would have done anything to save it.
確實如此
That's true.
甚至開除我也在所不惜
Including firing me.
真奇怪 如此鼎鼎大名的偵探
You know, for such a smart detective,
也能犯這種蠢
you're awfully stupid.
他們沒有取消這部劇
They weren't canceling us.
他們只是把我換掉了
They were replacing me.
這可是我自己的劇啊
On my own show.
或許我們應該坐下 冷靜地談談
Perhaps we should sit down and calmly discuss this.
我很冷靜 我來這就為了要回我的工作
I came here calm. I came here to ask for my job back.
你知道這有多羞辱人嗎
Do you have any idea how humiliating that is?
然後他拒絕了你 於是你就
And when he said no, that's when you--
我誰都沒殺啊
I didn't kill anybody!
那就把槍放下
Then put the gun down.
你真的會傷到人
You could actually hurt someone in here.
這不再是個遊戲了
Th-This isn't a game anymore.
這從來不是個遊戲
This was never a game.
這是我的事業
This is my career.
我才不要放下槍
And I'm not putting the gun down
因為我不是殺人兇手
because I'm not the killer.
但這裡總有一個人是
But someone else here is.
我嗎
Me?
我是被請來這查案的
I was brought here to solve this case.
我知道
I know.
艾米莉亞·穆恩 偉大的偵探
Amelia Moon, the great detective.
她到哪兒 死亡就會跟到哪
Death just seems to follow her wherever she goes.
不 這太離譜了 我
No, this is crazy. I--
還有你這個穿著奇裝異服的古怪朋友
And your strange friend in his odd clothes,
看起來完全沒有七情六慾
so devoid of emotion.
總是在觀察
Always watching,
學習
studying.
嘿 等等
Hey, wait a minute.
你是電視台派來的嗎
Did the network send you?
你就是替代我的人嗎
Are you my replacement?
不 你這個蠢貨
No! You idiot!
他只是來幫我的
He was just here to help me!
我不是 我沒有
I-I didn't. I didn't.
史波克 史波克
Spock? Spock?
我沒事
I'm okay.
謝天謝地
Oh, thank God.
怎麼了
What is it?
是你
It's you.
你就是兇手
You're the killer.
你去假裝診斷系統的時候
You poisoned Lupino's cup
在盧皮諾的杯子裡下了毒
when you were "running diagnostics."
你弄壞了吊燈 然後救了我
You sabotaged the chandelier, then saved me from it.
然後
And then...
你殺了伍茲
you killed Woods.
很新穎的理論 但我沒有動機
A novel theory, but I have no motive.
我只是你的同事 協助你偵查案件
I am simply your colleague, assisting you with a case.
你甚至不是這個故事的一部分
You're not even a part of this story.
是我帶你來這兒的
I brought you here.
是你利用了我 你才能出現
Because you made me bring you here.
你不是我的同事
You're not my colleague.
你是個全息投影
You're a hologram.
自我進入全息甲板的那一刻你就在這了
You have been since the moment I walked into the holodeck.
我讓計算機為我量身訂製一個謎題
I asked the computer for a mystery made for me,
然後你就是謎題 因為
and it gave me you, because, well,
電腦看到了我之前和真的史波克在一起 並且
it watched me earlier with the real Spock, and...
它知道我從不懷疑他
...it knew I'd never suspect him.
非常精彩 拉安·努尼恩·辛格上尉
Bravo, Lieutenant La'An Noonien-Singh.
你解決了這個謎題
You have solved the mystery.
計算機
Computer...
結束程序吧
...end program?
儘管全息甲板技術確實有潛力
While holodeck technology certainly holds promise,
但是風險實在是多於它的優點
the risks outweigh the potential benefits.
我們不推薦把該裝置安裝在現役星艦上
We do not recommend the device be installed on active ships...
目前如此
at this time.
我們乾脆建議把它用箱子鎖起來
How about we recommend that it be locked
埋進暗無天日的地裡吧
in a box deep underground somewhere?
呃 如果我可以小小的補充一下
Well, if I could just make one wee, tiny addendum.
它只是需要一個獨立的服務器機房
It-it just needs a dedicated server room
然後供能也得是獨立的
and power source that--
記在報告裡吧 不過只作為腳註
Include it in the report, but as a footnote.
用小字體
In small print.
中尉
Lieutenant?
你知道在船上我們有多少船員嗎
Do you know how many crew we have on board?
呃
Uh...
203個人
203.
具體的講 有整整203名星際艦隊最優秀的現役軍官
Specifically, 203 of the finest Starfleet has to offer.
當你需要幫助的時候
There is never any reason
永遠沒有必要獨自去抗擔子
to do something alone when you need help.
是啊 但如果有呢
Yeah, but what if there is?
在馭星者號遇上戈恩人的前一週
About a week before my last ship ran into the Gorn,
我當時正在建傳感器陣列
I was building a sensor array.
我好像發現了一些異常
I thought I saw some anomalies,
但是沒有時間去調查它
but I didn't have time to finish it.
我的指揮官說她會去看看 但她沒有 然後我們就
My CO said she would, but she didn't, and then we...
馭星者號的事情不是你的錯
What happened on the Stardiver wasn't your fault.
我們的工作很艱難
What we do here is hard,
而且時常會發生不幸
and sometimes bad things happen.
但船員們是一個團體
But this crew is a team.
知道何時向別人尋求幫助不是什麼弱點
Knowing when to ask for help isn't a weakness.
而是一種力量
It's a strength.
也是艦長和我非常重視的品德
One the captain and I value very highly.
感謝你願意來完成我們之前的課程
Thank you for agreeing to finish our lesson from earlier.
不用謝
Of course.
計算機 播放歌單 史波克二十一號
Computer, begin playlist: Spock 21.
所以 我想你對全息甲板的謎題測試
So I take it the holodeck mystery test was not
不是很滿意
to your satisfaction.
我想要的是單人向的解密
Well, I requested a solo mystery,
但是全息甲板讓我誤以為我需要一個搭檔
yet the holodeck led me to believe I needed a partner.
我找了你
You.
它誤解了你的要求嗎
It misunderstood your prompt?
這個嘛 我想它理解的非常到位
That, I think it understood perfectly.
我只是沒有想到
I just didn't take into account
全息甲板比我想的更了解我
that the holodeck knew me better than I realized.
它給了我一個我從未設想到的嫌疑人
It gave me a suspect I never anticipated.
十分有趣的技術
Interesting technology.
你是怎麼破除它的誘導的
How did you deduce this twist?
我一開始真被騙到了
I didn't at first.
完全跟著錯誤的線索鏈調查
I was looking for clues in all the wrong places.
但我現在理解了它到底出的是什麼題
But now I understand the puzzle it built for me.
願聞其詳
And what was that?
它用全息投影復刻了一個你
It created a holographic version of you
頭腦清晰 有邏輯
that was clear-headed, logical.
冷漠
Cold.
這麼形容我很正確
Words that have been used to describe me.
但我
But I...
我了解你
I know you.
我知道你跳舞時手臂抱著我的感覺
I know the feel of your arms when we dance.
我知道我們注視彼此的眼神裡有什麼
I... know the way we look into each other's eyes.
他看我的樣子和你不同
He didn't look at me like that.
也許我之前誤判了什麼
Or perhaps I've misread the situation.
之前跳舞那次
Earlier today...
我想知道是不是我想太多了
I wondered if it was I who had misunderstood.
因為有那麼一瞬間 我以為你想
Because for a moment, I thought that you wanted...
那 你也想嗎
And... did you also want?
我們要吃掉人類涼皮
We will eat the human food-pies!
是涼皮 還是糧堆來著
Is it... is it pies, or piles?
是堆
It's piles.
皮嗎
Pies?
向左
Left.
回來 向右 向右
And back. Right, right, right.
往右啊
And right!
這個怎麼樣
How's this?
這樣呢
How about this?
天殺的
Goddamn it!
小心衣服
Costumes!
各位 這是星雲嗎
You guys, is it "nebula"?
哇哦
Whoa!
那我們需要幫助
Then we'll need a leg up.
-這是我的台詞 -我以為這是我的台詞
- That's my line! - I thought I had the leg bit.
-台詞 -什麼 為什麼你要講這句
- Line? - What? Why would you have the leg bit?
我不知道 我以為我有這句台詞
I-I don't know. I thought I had the leg bit.
這很明顯是我的台詞 是艦長的台詞
Well, it's clearly my line! It's a captain's line.
為什麼她有這句台詞
Why would she have the leg bit?
這是我的台詞
It's my line.
是啊 我們正在等信號
Yeah. We're waiting on sound.
紅色皮革 黃色皮革
Red leather, yellow leather.
嘿
Hey.
我收不到她的信號了
I've lost her.
我收不到了
I've lost her!
老天啊 我只是想跨過這個椅子
Jesus Christ. I was trying to get my leg over.
這個椅子 就不能
Can... this chair...
有人能修下這個椅子嗎 求求了
Can someone fix the chair? Please?
我不能坐這玩意
I'm... I w... I can't work like...
開門
Open the door.
救命 救命
Help. Help!
好了 我扶住你了
Yeah, I got you.